Antonio Riccelli

Email: anton.riccelli@gmail.com | Guildford, Surrey GU1 | linkedin.com/in/antonioriccelli

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Supply Chain Analyst with experience in the pharmaceutical industry. My proactive approach in analysis and attention to detail resulted in many successful project implementations and process improvements, such as cutting time-wasting activities by 90% by automating the calculation of monthly quotas for all customers across the UK. **Fluent in Italian and English. Core competencies include**:

Report and dashboard creation \cdot Sales Analysis \cdot Process Improvement \cdot Advanced Excel \cdot SQL \cdot PostgreSQL \cdot Python (Numpy and Pandas) \cdot Git \cdot Tableau \cdot Qliksense \cdot HTML \cdot CSS \cdot Javascript \cdot Bootstrap \cdot SASS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sanofi UK via Ashfield Healthcare UDG (as contractor) · Guildford/Reading · 2018 – Present

Supply Chain Analyst

Oversees and analyses the distribution and supply of a portfolio of 200 products to wholesalers and pharmacies across the UK. Manages customer quotas and ensures accounts' master data integrity. Oversees launch of new products in the UK market. Develops and maintains dashboards and reports for purposes of sales and risk analysis, forecasting and planning. Collaborates on creation of new SOPs and works on projects focused on process and business improvement and automation.

- Successfully contributed to automating calculation of customers' quotas by completely re-designing internal system and script, gaining back 90% of work time
- Querying several different data sources, minimized out-of-stock risk by developing a daily sales tracking dashboard used by the leadership and supply chain lead team
- Created a customers' queries tracker for all teams involved that allowed process streamlining and minimised time-wasting activities and risk of errors
- Nominated 4 times for "Star Award" for excellent performance and commitment to Sanofi values

Customer Service Executive

Responds to incoming customer queries via phone and email. Handles complaints ensuring timely resolution. Manages customer service performance and runs daily exception reports for sales, stocks and master data. Ensures all information related to potential adverse events is reported to Pharmacovigilance. Gathers feedback and data about market intelligence from customers and shares findings with relevant teams.

- Reduced volume of daily electronic orders failures by 90% in 4 months by analyzing root causes and coordinating resolution with internal and external stakeholders
- Improved customer satisfaction KPI by 30% by proactively resolving complaints at first point of contact
- Consistently met performance milestones in speed, accuracy and volume and promoted to Supply Chain Analyst in 7 months

Barclays Bank UK PLC · Farnham/Guildford · 2016 - 2018

Moment Banker

Provides customers with expert advice on products and services and introduces them to the Barclays' proposition. Opens current and savings accounts, loans and provides insurances. Identifies business leads and

hands them over to relevant teams i.e. mortgage, premier, investment etc. Introduces customers to digital options. Manages his own diary and proactively seeks new appointments. Mentors and upskills junior members.

- Opened up several loans for an overall return of over £150K
- Provided new leads to our Premier and Mortgages teams resulting in 3 new customers remortgaging and over 5 new customers added to our Premier portfolio
- Constantly mentioned by name in customer feedback reviews with scores ranging from 8/10 to 10/10

Essential Banker

Acts as first point of contact for customers in the branch. Operates the front counter by processing deposits, withdrawals, funds transfers and general account servicing. Deals with queries, concerns and complaints. Operates the counting house by processing business transactions, cash management and reconciliation and security procedures. Provides leads to Moment Bankers.

- Identified several fraudulent transactions avoiding losses for over £1K
- Provided several leads for loans and insurances to Senior colleagues resulting in returns for over £5K
- Tactfully handled many distressed customers and prevented complaints from escalating, avoiding reputational damage and loss for the business
- Worked in back of house handling branch cash-flow and high-value business transactions

Compass Group UK - Costa Coffee · Guildford (Royal Surrey County Hospital) · 2015 - 2016

Barista - Shift Leader

Provides excellent customer services in a hectic, fast-paced environment. Prepares all drinks and food in line with Costa standards and recipes. Operates cash register and monitors store's cashflow and availability. Completes daily cleaning schedule and carries out cleaning duties. Outlines weekly and daily rota for all staff members and manages lunch breaks. Monitors stock levels and places orders with wholesalers when required. Upsells specific products and signature coffee flavors.

- Served over 100 customers per day in a hectic and fast-paced environment
- Nominated "Star of the Month"
- Achieved target for monthly bonus several times
- Analyzed performance and produced a report highlighting inefficiencies and ways to improve
- Worked as Shift Leader during my last 4 months

EDUCATION

- Full Stack Development Certification (in progress) Start2Impact.it
- Programming for Data Science with Python Nanodegree Program, **Udacity.com**
- SQL Nanodegree Program (SQL, NOSQL, Postgresgl, MongoDB), **Udacity.com**
- Introduction to Programming (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python), **Udacity.com**
- Responsive Web Design (HTML/CSS) Certification, freeCodeCamp.org
- Business Analytics Nanodegree Program (Statistics, Excel, SQL, Tableau), Udacity.com
- Bachelor's Degree in Foreign Languages and Literatures (110/110), Naples Eastern University -Naples, Italy
- High School Diploma in Foreign Languages and Literatures (98/100), High School "Guido Tassinari" -Naples, Italy